Guide to the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration Records,
1943-1949
United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.
103 microfilm reels.
Columbia University. Herbert H. Lehman Suite and Papers, New York, NY.
4078516
History
United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration was established in 1943. Its purpose was to provide for the relief of war victims in any area under the control of any of the United Nations. Its operations came to an end in 1946.
Scope and Content
Included are correspondence, memoranda, documents, minutes, committee reports, and miscellaneous documents from the files of the Bureau of Administration; Office of the Diplomatic Advisor; Office of the Director General; Office of the Economic Advisor; Office of Far Eastern Affairs; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Historian; Office of Public Information; and Secretariat Executive Officer.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 9 series:
Series I: Bureau of Administration
Series II. Office of the Diplomatic Advisor
Series III. Office of the Director General
Series IV. Office of the Economic Advisor
Series V. Office of the Far Eastern Affairs
Series VI. Office of the General Counsel
Series VII. Office of the Historian
Series VIII. Office of Public Information
Series IX. Secretariat Executive Office
Subjects
Herbert H. Lehman Collections (Columbia University).; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.--Bureau of Administration.; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.--Office of the Diplomatic Advisor.; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.--Office of the Director General.; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.--Office of the Economic Advisor.; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.--Office of Far Eastern Affairs.; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.--Office of the General Counsel.; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.--Office of the Historian.; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.--Secretariat Executive Officer.; Refugees.; Refugees, Political.; International relief.; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
Reels FE4 and H15 are missing and are not accessible at this time.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
Correspondence, memoranda, documents, minutes, committee reports
- Series I: Bureau of Administration
  - Subseries Subseries I.1: Executive Office. Subject File
    - Abbreviations (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Accounting (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Accounts and Audit (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Accounts and Audit, Director (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Accounts, Special Purpose (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Analysis Division (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Analysis - A.A. Memoranda to/from Chief, Division (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Analysis Division Reports (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Equipment and Supplies (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Orders, Draft (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Organization (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Organization (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Planning, Director, Correspondence (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Services (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Services, Director, Correspondence (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Services, Headquarters, Correspondence (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Administrative Services, Memos (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Agreement, H.I.A.S.ter (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Allowances (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Allowances, Clothing (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Areas, Bureau of (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Areas, Bureau of (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Areas, Bureau of (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Audit Division (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Authorizations (H.P. Van Gelder) (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Automobile Accidents (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Budget (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Budget (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Budget, Administrative, 1945 (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Budget - Corson - Finance and Administration Files (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Budget Division (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Budget - Public Information (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Budget and Management Division (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Cable Section (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Candidates, Chief Accountant (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Candidates, Director of Accounts (Box BA/1, Folder Side 1)
    - Civil Service Panel (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Commissioner of Public Buildings (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Committees: (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Central Committee (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Chinese Technology Trainees, Standing Committee on (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Classification Committees (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Contribution Committee (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Employee Remuneration, Committee on (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Equitable Distribution of UNRRA (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Commissary and PX Facilities (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Commodity Accounting - Finance and Administration (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Communications (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Communication Section, Administrative Services (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Communications Survey (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Communications - Weigel's File (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Conscientious Objectors (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Contributions (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Contributions (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Cooperatives (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Council Sessions (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - 2nd Council Session - Documentation (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - 2nd Council Session - Memoranda, J.J. Corson (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - 3rd Council Session - Preparation (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - 4th Council Session (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - 4th Council Session (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - 4th Council Session - Personnel and Duplicates (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - 4th Council Session (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - 5th Council Session - Reports (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Country Mission, Office of, Correspondence (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Diplomatic Adviser (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Diplomatic Adviser, Office of, Correspondence (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Director General (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - The Director General 200 (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Memos (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Office of (Box BA/1, Folder Side 2)
    - Policy Issue Meeting, 1945 (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Reports (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Reports, 9/15 - 12/31 (1944) (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Report to Council Reports, Monthly, to the Central Committee(see also Committees - Central) (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Displaced Persons Division (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Displaced Persons Division, Memos (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Economic and Financial Advisers in Missions (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Encumbrances (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - European Missions Reserves (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Far East Planning (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Far Eastern Division, Memos (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Field Letters (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Field Office Reports (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Filing Equipment (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Filing System, Gills La Salle Building (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Finance and Administration (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Bureau of Finance and Administration (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Memoranda (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Operating Program, 1945 (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Weekly Letter to the European Regional Office (ERO) (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Finance Division (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Finance Reports (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Financial Adviser (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Financial Adviser (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Findings (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Flags (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Food and Agricultural Organization (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Foreign Economic Administration (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Foreign Liquidation Commission - State (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Fund, $250,00 Revolving (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - General Bulletins - Correspondence (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Hall, Tom, Correspondence (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Harris, J.P., Letters from (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Health Division (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Hendrickson, (Roy F.) (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Hendrickson - Cables (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Hendrickson, Memoranda (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - History, UNRRA (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Howell, Harry E. (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Immunities Legislation (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Import Requirements (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Insurance, Group Life, Insurance Claims Branch, Division of Finance (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Insurance, Life (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Insurance, Marine, General Council (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Internal Audit Division Reports (Box BA/2, Folder Side 1)
    - Internal Audit Reports (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Inventory (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2 Side 2)
    - Investigation Division Reports (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Jackson, Commander R.G.A., Sr. Deputy Director General (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Jackson, R.G. A. - Office of Director General (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Katzin, Colonel (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Labeling (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Leather (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Legal Counsel (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Lend-Lease (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Letters of Credit (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Lloyd, J.E. (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Local Currency (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Manuals (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Administrative Services Manual (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Finance and Administration Organization Manual (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Personnel Manual, Draft Chapters (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Meetings (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Notes on Meetings, Conversations, etc. (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Finance and Administration Staff Meetings (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Personnel Division Meetings (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Policy Issue Meetings - Minutes Indexing Completed (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Staff Meetings (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Staff Meetings - Bureau of Finance and Administration (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Staff Meetings - Every Monday, 11:45, Director General's Office (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Staff Meetings, Tuesday (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Memos, All Bureaus and Divisions (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Memos, Office (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Military (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, A - (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Mission Chiefs - Personnel Suggestions (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Neutral, Stateless, Ex-Enemy Countries (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Organization (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Organization, UNRRA (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Overseas Administration Requirements Branch, Rand (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Pan-American (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Parnell, Correspondence (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Personnel (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Administrative Services Personnel (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Displaced Persons Personnel, Target Reports (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Division, Personnel (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Division, Personnel (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Field Employees - Personnel Division (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Field Personnel Exclusive of London as of April 30, 1944 (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Finance and Administration Personnel - Missions (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - General, Personnel (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - General Correspondence, PersonnelHeadquarters Personnel by Organization Location as of April 30, 1944 (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Headquarters Personnel by Salary Levels as of April 30, 1944Loans of Personnel to Other Organizations (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Member Governments - Personnel (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Policy, Personnel (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Vacancies - Hdqtrs Personnel as of April 30, 1944 (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Policy - Administrative Orders, etc. (Box BA/2, Folder Side 2)
    - Policy - Memos (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Postal Services - International (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - The President (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Procedural Coordination Division Director, Correspondence (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Procedural Coordination Division, Draft Adm. Orders & Bulletins (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Property Accountability (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Provident Fund (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Public Information (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Public Information (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Purchase and Supply Branch, Office of Chief (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Recommendations, Corson to Gill and to Lehman (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Recruitment Outside U.S. Consuls - DC (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Regional Liaison, Correspondence Office (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Repatriation (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Reports - Finance and Administration Policy (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Reports - Miscellaneous (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Representation Allowances (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Resolution 80, Implementation of (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Resources, UNRRA (Statements of estimated resources, etc.) (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Run-down (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Salary Scales, Revision of U.S. (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Sayre Mission (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Secretariat (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Secretariat (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Security Arrangements (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Security Branch Administrative Services (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Security, Building (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Security Instructions for UNRRA, Allied Force Headquarters (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Security Representatives cont'd Security Violations (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Selective Service Memoranda (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Senators, U.S., Correspondence (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Services, Bureau of, Correspondence (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Severance Pay (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - SHAEF (Supreme Headquarters Allied Expeditionary Force) (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Space - Administrative Services (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Staff Society (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - State Department, U.S., Correspondence (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Statistics & Reports (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Supply, Bureau of (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Supply, Bureau of, Correspondence (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Taxes (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Training Center, Finance and Administration Persons at (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Training Center, Reports to (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Training Division - Minutes, Reports (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Training Division - Memos (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Training Division - Reports, Minutes (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Training Nationals Member Governments (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Training Program (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Training Section (Box BA/3, Folder Side 1)
    - Travel (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Travel Clearance, Wadsworth (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Travel Memos - Administrative Services (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Travel Section - Administrative Services (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Treasurer (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Treasurer (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Treasurer - K. Dayton (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Uniforms (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - UN - Clothing Collection Drive (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Voluntary Agencies - Welfare (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - War Department, U.S., Correspondence (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Welfare (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Workmen's Compensation (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
  - Subseries I.2: Executive Office. Country File
    - Albanian Mission (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Algiers (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Austrian Mission - Telephone Directory (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Balkan Mission- 3 folders plus: (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Audit Report (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Budget (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Liquidation Diary (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Liquidation Reports (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Belgium Mission (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Brazil (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - China (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - China Area Office (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - China Flight (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Czech Mission (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Denmark (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Ethiopian Mission (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Europe - Economic and Political Developments (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Europe - Office for (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Europe Survey of DP Operations - Katzin (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - European Regional Office (ERO) (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Closure Plan (Box BA/3, Folder Side 2)
    - Division of Responsibility - HQ and ERO (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Finance and Administration (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Miscellaneous Copies Printed Material Received from ERO (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Personnel as of April 30, 1944 (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Telephone Calls (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Finland (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - France (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - German Mission (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Germany (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Greece Mission (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Greek Branch (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Hungary (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - India (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Italian Mission - 2 folders plus: (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Agreement (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Directive (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Reports (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Korea (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Latin American Mission (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Luxembourg (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Mediterranean Theater (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - MERRA (Middle East Relief & Rehabilitation Adm.) Camp Operations (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Middle East Office (MEO) (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Middle East Office (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - NARC (North African Refugee Center) (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - The Netherlands (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - New Delhi Office (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - New York Office (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Norway (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Philippeville Camp (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Philippeville - Requisitions (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Philippines - General (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Philippine Mission (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - Polish Mission (Box BA/4, Folder Side 1)
    - San Francisco Office (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Southwest Pacific Area Office (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Sweden (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Switzerland (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Turkey Contributions (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - USSR - Contributions (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - USSR - Mission (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Yugoslavia (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Yugoslavia (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
  - Subseries I.3: Personnel and Management Division. Subject File
    - Brethren Service Committee Correspondence (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - E.O.D. (Employees Overseas Division?) and Termination Lists - 1946 (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Headquarters Employees in Active Pay Status (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Class 1 List by Nationalities (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Directors & Deputy Directors presently employed in Displaced Persons (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Germany and Terminated Directors & Deputy Directors who have been terminated after 1 Jan. 1947 (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - UNRRA Grade 12, 13, 14, 15's and Ungraded (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Directories on UNRRA Personnel (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - UNRRA Personnel Transfered to IRQ (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Council Meetings (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - A - E (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - F - J (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - K - M (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - N - R (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - S - V (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - W - Z (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Class 1 Personnel List (Box BA/4, Folder Side 2)
    - Class 1 List Compiled by Personnel Division (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - UNRRA & South African Continental Personnel in DP Operations (Germany) (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - UNRRA Western Hemisphere Personnel in DP Operation (Germany) (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - UNRRA London Personnel in DP Operation (Germany) (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - India Files (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Staff Employed by SWPA (Southwest Pacific Area Office) (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Fellowship (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Health Personnel (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - UNRRA Welfare Personnel in China Mission (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Personnel Employees - Liaison with Welfare Training Employees of Interest - Top Personnel with Welfare Background - Top Welfare Personnel terminated prior to 1 July 1946 (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - China Mission Staffing Authorization 1 Sept. 1947 (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Use of Nominal Roll for Information Desired on Personnel with China Experience (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - UNRRA China Office Directory of Home Addresses (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - UNRRA Class II Personnel in China (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - China Class II List UNRRA (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - China Fisheries Contract Personnel (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - BOTRA Employees (UNRRA WAE's) (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Bonus (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Bonus (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Bonus Plan (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Manuals (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Field Manual of Finance (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Finance Manuals (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Mission Administrative Services Manual (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Office Practices Manual (0PM) H.I.A.S.ter Copy (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Office Practices Manual - Cablegrams and Telegrams - Section 130 (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Office Practices Manual - General (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Operations Manual H.I.A.S.ter Copy (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Paragraphs Manual (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Personnel Inquiries Reference Manual, UNRRAPersonnel Management Manual (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Personnel Management Manual - Correspondence (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - Personnel Management Manual, Authority for (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - ERO Classification Manual (Box BA/5, Folder Side 1)
    - ERO Classification Manual (Box BA/5, Folder Side 2)
    - File Classification Manual (Box BA/5, Folder Side 2)
    - UNRRA Preparations Manual for Overseas Staff (Box BA/5, Folder Side 2)
    - Security Manual (Box BA/5, Folder Side 2)
    - Stenographers Handbook (Box BA/5, Folder Side 2)
    - McBee (Box BA/5, Folder Side 2)
    - McBee - Information (Box BA/5, Folder Side 2)
    - Instructions for McBee Code Clerk (Box BA/5, Folder Side 2)